SOFTWARE ENGINEER · FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Lisboa, Portugal

☑jmsfilipe@gmail.com | ♠jmsfilipe.com | ☑jmsfilipe | ஞjmsfilipe

"One day Alice came to a fork in the road and saw a Cheshire cat in a tree. 'Which road do I take?' she asked. 'Where do you want to go?' was his response. 'I don't know,' Alice answered. 'Then,' said the cat, 'it doesn't matter."

Summary _

Linkfire

Javascript developer with a passion for web and software development. I'm a professional with an excellent work ethic and a loyal worker focusing on the best outcomes. I've got a strong team spirit and a good sense of humor. Focused and efficient and good at communicating progress. I have experience working with many frameworks and libraries, including Vue (mostly 2, but already did some work on 3), Angular JS, Angular and Ionic. My front-end development approach follows best practices as well as usability guidelines with performance awareness. I always try to find the most scalable and modular solution for a problem, in order to avoid wasting time in the near future. Mobile compatibility is one of my main concerns, so I always focus on making my apps work on mobile devices nice and smooth.

Work Experience _____

Lisbon, Portugal / Copenhagen,

Denmark 2019 - 2022

2016 - 2019

2015 - 2016

SENIOR FRONT-END ENGINEER / TECH LEAD

- Tech lead responsibilities for the partners team
- Build high-reach product from scratch, used as a widget by clients
- Challenging work to provide the widget as a web component for the partners to use
- · Close relation with the designers, in order to deliver small incremental deliveries of the widget
- Project management for a large feature adding contextual targeting to the widget
- · Worked in 4 different projects widget, ad management, widget backoffice, contextual targeting
- Onboarding of new team members
- All SCRUM ceremonies planning, daily, review, retrospective
- · Vue, web components, css/scss, AWS services (Comprehend, Lambda, SQS, API gateway), Jira, Lokalise, GitHub actions, REST
- Code reviews and unit tests

Helpr Tech Lisbon, Portugal

FRONT-END ENGINEER

Responsible for the development of helpr's CMS.
Built with Angular (with unit testing) and it is responsive.

- Features include the ability to send, filter and target push notifications to specific audiences on mobile phones. As well as user listing, content editing and analytics.
- Code quality, testability and consistent project structure.
- Development of hybrid apps, using Ionic.
- · AngularJS, Angular and Ionic Framework. SCSS.

bimK Oeiras, Portugal

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Developed a Sims-like portal, that offered object for architects to use in their projects.
 Responsible for developing the analytics front-end, allowing for the user to switch between various chart types, and view statistics by country,
- Play framework, AngularJS HTML5 and SCSS. PostgreSQL, Java, ElasticSearch.

Museu Nacional de História Natural e da Ciência

Lisbon, Portugal

Web developer

in a world-map.

2014 - 2016

- Designed the museum's website structure and created it in Drupal.
- In a different project, I helped to structure a citizen science platform.

Innovation Makers Oeiras, Portugal

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

2014 (summer intership)

- Developed a server side prototype for a banking kiosk.
- Experimenting a websockets protocol to establish the connection between the server and the interface.
- C#, websockets. Javascript, HTML.

Primedrinks Lisbon, Portugal

TRAINEE 2013 (summer internship)

- Setup required systems, maintaining network structure, helpdesk.
- Overall intersting experience, mainly because of daily contact with people: understanding their needs and figure the best quality/cost solution.
- Microsoft technologies.

INEDC-ID Lisbon, Portugal

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Development of a serious game aiming to explain the basic life support protocol.
- C# and Unity game engine.
- Awarded with a grade of 17/20 by the jury.
- · web.tecnico.ulisboa.pt/jorge.s.filipe/work/sbv

Education

Instituto Superior Técnico, Universidade de Lisboa

Oeiras, Portugal

2012 (summer internship)

MASTERS IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2013 - 2015

- · My thesis, "Where Have I Been Visualizing Personal Geolocation Data" explored visual queries with personal semantics, regarding personal geolocation data.
- Data cleaning of GPS tracks smoothing of paths and error removal.
- · Spatial databases and queries based on the tracks, find information like: in which days did I spent more than 5 hours at University.
- Visual querying interface simple drag and edit interface to reproduce queries in an easy way.
- · Python, PostGIS, Javascript, HTML.
- avg. grade: 16/20

Instituto Superior Técnico, Universidade de Lisboa

Lisboa, Portugal

BACHELOR IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2010 - 2013

2007 - 2010

· avg. grade: 13/20

Escola Secundária Damião de Goes

Alenquer, Portugal

Highschool

Science and Technology

Extracurricular Activity_

LAGE2 - Laboratório de Apoio à Gestão de Actividades Extracurriculares dos Estudantes

Oeiras, Portugal

DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS AND EVENTS AND VICE PRESIDENT

2014 - 2015

- Event coordination and management in a student group at IST-Taguspark.
- Planning workshops, conferences and talks for the campus students.

Instituto Superior Técnico, Universidade de Lisboa

Oeiras, Portugal

TEDxIST ORGANIZER

· Part of TEDxIST 2015 team.

2015

• With previous experience, helped the team to succeed on another edition of TEDxIST.

Instituto Superior Técnico, Universidade de Lisboa

Oeiras, Portugal

TEDXIST COORDINATOR

- Team leader in the planning of the event, from October to March.
- TEDxIST 2014 host and coordinator.

ALAMBI – Associação para o estudo e defesa do ambiente do concelho de Alenquer

Alenquer, Portugal

ENVIRONMENTAL VOLUNTEER

2009 - 2016

- · Creation and maintenance of the website.
- · Publication and presentation of environmental related material.

Skills_

Development

· HTML5, CSS3, Javascript ES6 (Functional, Modular and Object Oriented), Single Page Applications, Web Components, Crossbrowser Compatibility, Git, GitHub actions, AWS services

APIs

· REST APIs, Google Maps API, Google Ad Manager

JUNE 21, 2022 JORGE M. SALDANHA · RÉSUMÉ

Javascript frameworks

• Vue2, Vue3, AngularJS, Angular, Ionic, Jest, Selenium, Protractor.

Soft skills

• Enthusiasm, problem solving, teamwork, decision making, quick learning, determination, responsibility, proactivity, result-driven.

Interests

• Multimedia, interfaces, web development, programming, computer science, tech conferences, game development, serious games, quantified self, photography, bike, swimming, traveling.